Monika Rangta

Experienced IT Project Management Executive having 4+ years of experience with a background in web and crypto software development. Looking for the new opportunities in Finland to work as a Full-stack software developer. Currently enhancing my development skills by learning several programming languages like React.js and Python. As an IT Project Manager, I oversaw a range of critical projects like Crypto exchanges, Wallets applications from conception to delivery.

ODÖBELNINKATU 3B 11, 00260 HELSINKI

(+358) 451686586

monikarangta@icloud.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/monika-rangta/

https://github.com/mrangta

EXPERIENCE

Webcom Systems Pvt. Ltd., India— IT Project Manager

JUNE 2017 - APRIL 2018

- Manages major parts of the projects ranging from project onboarding and execution, bridging the gap between development teams and clients, QA activities and reporting.
- Oversaw 10+ major Crypto development projects and 8+ digital marketing projects.
- Implemented successfully Crypto Wallet App Development Projects based on javascript, node.js.
- Hosted various websites on Godaddy, Namecheap, Hostgator through Filezilla, SmartFTP and C-Panel and implemented Cloudflare DDOS protection on various websites.

Vinove Software and Services Pvt. Ltd., India — *Project Coordinator and Quality Assurance*

OCTOBER 2016 - MAY 2017

- Expertise in creating wireframes, annotations on Axure and mockflow.com
- Managed 20+ Projects of (Core PHP, PHP Frameworks (Cake PHP, Cl), CMS(E-commerce, Wordpress, Woocommerce, Joomla, Magento), Mobile Applications, Web Applications, HTML/HTML5 & CSS3 Projects, Responsive Projects, etc.)
- Uses Zoho Project Management tools to monitor working hours,
 Project Sprints and for daily updates.
- Efficiently handle a node of almost 12 members, assign tasks on a daily basis and track tasks status at the end of the day.
- As QA, responsible for writing test cases and report the bugs.

GoldVIP Technology Solutions Private Limited, India — Senior Relationship Manager

SEPTEMBER 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2016

 Collaborates with the sales and development teams to launch app (CrownIT) feature on time and within budget.

SKILLS

Coding Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, React.js, .Net, C#

Web Administration (Web hosting, Domain Forwarding): Godaddy, Namecheap, Hostgator, Heroku.

Agile Project Management

Wireframes and Annotations designing

Team Management

Client Handling

Quality Assurance

SOFTWARES

Zoho Projects

Basecamp

Jira

Axure

Mockflow

Visual Studio Code

Atom

GitHub

Filezilla

Visual Studio

SQL SERVER 2008 R3 Express

- Handled the team of 5 members and maintain the Insight Turnaround Time (TAT) report of the team members.
- Coordinate with the Digital Marketing team in order to run social awareness campaigns, ads and email marketing.
- Uses Salesforce and Insight for compliance check, Increased company sales by 28%.

Kerviz Technology, India — *Technical Executive*

JULY 2014 - AUGUST 2015

- Uses Project management tools FreedCamp, Basecamp to track project activities.
- Built the 10+ websites using HTML, CSS and C#. Decreased rework by 23% and costs by 15%.
- Manual testing (QA) of various projects related to web and mobile applications.

Hacxad Infotech Pvt. Ltd., India — *Junior .Net Developer*

FEBRUARY 2014 - JULY 2014

- Developed a web portal for online coupons and deals using C#
- Built various e-commerce websites on Opencart and a classified website on Os-class.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering, Himachal Pradesh University, India

AUGUST 2010 - JUNE 2014

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate in ReactJS Web Development, Udemy

February 2019

Certified in General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), Alison

December 2018

Certified in Website Designing, Global Vision Technologies, India

APRIL 2016 - AUGUST 2016

Certified in Software Development - JAVA, .Net, ZCC Group of Corporate Training and Technical Education, India

AUGUST 2010 - JUNE 2010

PROJECTS MANAGED

Opencart:

https://zarela.co.uk/

http://www.luxushair.com/

http://vintelegram.dk/

Wordpress:

http://justonejoke.com/

http://www.emoneyindeed.com/

http://fenestra.coop/

https://fundingpro.com.au/

http://ipgeniussolutions.com/

Wordpress & woo-commerce:

http://broncowine.com/

http://blazequel.com/

http://vflaudio.com/

https://www.kurthelectronic.de/

http://cbsbtysupply.com/

Magento:

https://www.fashionplanet24.com/

https://www.visionembroidery.com/

Android App:

SoarIndiavoice

Crypto wallet app on play store:

Koindirekt

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi